Guide to the Dimension Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Dimension Production Materials, Series II; 18.67; (19 boxes)
  - Unidentified
    - Other materials
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk 18
- Dimension Business Records, Series III; 10; (10 boxes)
  Records consist of original file groups of business and subscription records created by A. Leslie Willson, followed by unsorted files. Other related materials may be found in Series I, Subject Files.
  - Business Records, circa 1966- 1982 (Box 51)
    Includes records relating to the founding of Dimension, correspondence with University of Texas Dean W. Gordon Whaley about funding, correspondence with other funding agencies, financial accounts, and early distribution, subscription, and exchange lists.
  - Business Records (Box 52)
  - Business Records (Box 53)
  - Subscription Records (Box 53)
    Accounting files for contributors and subscribers to Dimension, including individuals, libraries, and other institutions. Includes some correspondence between Willson and subscribers. Files are labeled with names and identification numbers.
  - Subscription Records (Box 54)
  - Subscription Records (Box 55)
  - Subscription Records (Box 56)
  - Subscription Records (Box 57)
  - Subscription Records (Box 58)
  - Subscription Records (Box 59)
  - Unsorted files (Box 60)
- Writings, Series IV; 6; (6 boxes)
  Most writings are manuscripts, typescripts, or photocopies.
  Organized into five subseries: Writings by A. Leslie Willson; Translations by A. Leslie Willson; Translations by Jeanne Willson; Writings by Others; and Translations by Others. Within each subseries, writings are arranged alphabetically by title or genre; translations are arranged alphabetically by original author and title.
  - Writings by A. Leslie Willson
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Audiovisual Material
    - Academic papers (Box 60)
    - "The Author as Artist" (Box 60)
      Apparently not published
    - Essays (Box 61)
      Essays include: "The Portrait of Berlin in Lyric Poetry," "The Many Faces of Censorship in the Federal Republic of Germany," "Constancy and Variation: The Short Story in Germany," "German Literature in the Twentieth Century" (for Columbia Dictionary of Modern European Literature, 2nd edition), interview with Heinrich Böll, essays about literary translation
      Some essays are accompanied by related correspondence and source materials
      With a set of essays by other authors on the topic of translation
    - German Library (Continuum). Volume 99, Contemporary German Fiction, and Volume 100, Contemporary German Stories (Box 62)
      Includes correspondence with Volkmar Sander, general editor
    - "In Search of Authors: Letters to Jeanne", 1979 February- May (Box 62)
      About his literary meetings and activities in Germany
    - Three Contemporary German Novellas (Continuum), 2001 (Box 62)
    - A Tribute to Hermann Weigand (festschrift), 1982 (Box 62)
  - Translations by A. Leslie Willson
    - Becker, Jürgen. Margins (Box 62)
    - Brecht, B. Fatzer (translated by Willson, Andrzej Wirth, and David J. Ward) (Box 62)
    - Buch, Hans Christoph. Haiti Chérie (Box 62)
    - Buch, Hans Christoph. Kain und Abel in Afrika (Box 63)
    - Buch, Hans Christoph. Uebung mit Meistern (Box 63)
    - Goering, Reinhard. Seeschlacht (Box 63)
    - Grass, Günter. Uptight (Box 63)
    - Handke, Peter. Self-Accusation (Box 63)
    - Handke, Peter. Tongue-Lashing (Box 63)
    - Höllerer, Walter. Systems and Other Poems (Box 63)
    - Johnson, Uwe. A Part of New York (Box 63)
    - Kahler, Erich. The Internalization of Narrative (Box 63)
    - Kieseritzky, Ingomar. Divergence and Control (Box 63)
    - Koch, Werner. Before Golgotha (Box 63)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. Innerfar & Bluff, or The Southern Cross (Box 63)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. My Uncle Tom (Box 63)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. Piranesi's Dream (Box 63)
    - Krüger, Michael. The Man in the Tower (Box 63)
    - Kunert, Günter. In the Name of Hats (Box 63)
    - Kurzke, Hermann. Thomas Mann: Life as a Work of Art (Box 63)
    - Stadler, Arnold. Death and I, We Two (Box 64)
    - Strauss, Botho. The Dedication (Box 64)
    - Walser, Martin. Beautiful Anyway (Box 64)
    - Wellershoff, Dieter. Zero Hour Zero Minute and Zero Second (Box 64)
    - Weyrauch, Wolfgang. Points of Orientation (Box 64)
    - Wolf, Siegfried. Forge and Candle (Box 64)
    - Zoderer, Joseph. The Turtle Feast (Box 64)
    - Poetry (Box 64)
    - Other short translations (Box 64)
  - Translations by Jeanne Willson
    - Andres, Stefan. El Greco Paints the Grand Inquisitor (Box 64)
    - Dürrenmatt, Friedrich. Minatour (Box 64)
    - Mommsen, K., editor. Who is Goethe? (Box 64)
    - Schiller, Friedrich. Don Carlos (Box 64)
    - Wohmann, Gabriele. The Cherry Tree (Box 64)
  - Writings by Others
    - Bassett, James A. Fallen Angel (novel) (Box 64)
    - Dimensions: A. Leslie Willson & Contemporary German Arts and Letters (festschrift for Willson), 1993 (Box 65)
    - Ferber, Felicitas. Anuschka (children's story) (Box 65)
    - Geerk, Frank. Poem (Box 65)
    - Grass, Günter. Die Plebejer Proben den Aufstand (Box 65)
    - Gulden, Alfred. New York Notizen (Box 65)
    - Heissenbüttel, Helmut. Max unmittelbar vorm Einschlafen (radio play) (Box 65)
    - Hoffmann und Campe. Der Hoca Lese Brummer, 1979 (Box 65)
    - Kahn, Lisa. Flussbettworte (poems) (Box 65)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. Ein amerikanischer Traum (essay) (Box 65)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. Nachtpost (play) (Box 65)
    - Köpf, Gerhard. Winterweizen (novel) (Box 65)
    - Kortmann, Christian. Teure Pflaster (novel) (Box 65)
    - Kunert, Günter. Gast aus England (Box 65)
    - Levy, Herman. Geography: A World War II Thriller (play) (Box 65)
    - Maelzel, Richard. Poems: The Three Days of Love (Box 65)
    - Pabisch, Peter. Oswald Andrae und Walter A. Kreye, 1981 (Box 65)
    - Richter, Hans Werner, editor. Der Skorpion (Box 65)
      Photocopy of an issue dated 1948 January
    - Wohmann, Gabriele. Böse Streiche und andere Erzählungen, 1977 (Box 65)
      Unbound copy without illustration (Eremiten-Presse, 1977)
    - Essays by others about translation (Box 65)
    - Unidentified poem (printing plate) (Box 65)
  - Translations by Others
    Original author and title are followed by translator in parentheses.
    - Artmann, H. C. (Derk Wynand) (Box 65)
    - Augustin, Michael. Koslowski: Fifty-two Pointers from Hearsay (Margitt Verena Lehbert) (Box 65)
    - Bechtolsheim, Barbara von. Straelen (Louise E. Stoehr) (Box 65)
    - Bernhard, Thomas. Is It a Comedy? Is It a Tragedy? (Robert C. Fuhrmann) (Box 65)
    - Brandes, Sophie. Fritz Castalto's Guardian Angel (Skip Acuff) (Box 65)
    - Döblin, Alexander. The Curate (Eve Proctor) (Box 66)
    - Dürrenmatt, Friedrich. The Anabaptists (Lauren Friesen) (Box 66)
    - Frank, Karlhans. Hey Man, Have a Good One! (Melba D. Hackworth) (Box 66)
    - Fritz, Walter Helmut. Poems (Box 66)
    - Graf, Nico. Poems from Ins Auge Fassen (William Martin) (Box 66)
    - Handke, Peter. The Goalie's Anxiety at the Penalty Kick (M. Roloff) (Box 66)
    - Hilbig, Wolfgang. Die Weiber (Skip Rhudy) (Box 66)
    - Hildesheimer, Wolfgang. Time Out (Allan Blunden) (Box 66)
    - Hofmann, Gert. The Cramp (Christopher Middleton?) (Box 66)
    - Kahn, Lisa. While the Bluebonnets Slept (Lori Fischer) (Box 66)
    - Kirsch, Sarah. The Enormous Mountainous Waves at Sea (Carol Bedwell) (Box 66)
    - Koeppen, Wolfgang. Jugend (Paul F. Dvorak) (Box 66)
    - Laab, Joachim. I Feel Happy within My Four Walls (Hans W. Wuerth) (Box 66)
    - Lasker-Schüler, Else. Poems (Jane Curtis) (Box 66)
    - Meckel, Christoph. Drusch, the Lucky Magician (Carol Bedwell) (Box 66)
    - Meister, Ernst. Room without Walls (Georg M. Gugelberger) (Box 66)
    - Muschg, Adolf. Christel (Margret E. Studebaker) (Box 66)
    - Rinser, Luise. Abaelard's Love (Jean M. Snook) (Box 66)
    - Rys, Jan. Interview with a Very Important Personality (Billie R. Engels) (Box 66)
    - Timm, Uwe. The Dinner Party (Rebecca Penn) (Box 66)
    - Walter, Otto F. The Shimmering of the Water at Night (Glenn Lich) (Box 66)
    - Wehrli, Peter K. Catalogue of the 134 Most Important Observations during a Long Railway Journey (Foger Frood) (Box 66)
    - Wellersdorff, Dieter. Zero Zero Hours and No Seconds (Derk Wynand) (Box 66)
    - Widmer, Urs. Life in Frankfurt/M. (Michael P. Elzay) (Box 66)
    - Ziem, Jochen. Before the Last Frontier (Kurt Fickert) (Box 66)
    - Various authors. Poems (Max Knight) (Box 66)
- Personal Papers of A. Leslie Willson, Series V; 1.63; (3 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Letters of recommendation, course materials, and financial papers are restricted until 2085. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  The first subseries contains materials relating to professional organizations in which Willson was a member, held office, or attended meetings. The second subseries contains papers relating to Willson's teaching work at the University of Texas at Austin.
  Organized into two subseries: Professional Organizations and Meetings; and Teaching Materials.
  - Professional Organizations and Meetings
    - American Literary Translators Association, 1997 (Box 66)
    - American Translators Association, 1984-1992 (Box 66)
      Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disks 4-6, 8-11
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disks 1-3, 7
    - German Studies Association (Philadelphia), 1988 (Box 66)
    - Goethe-Institut: Berlin Meets Houston, Houston Meets Berlin, 1992 (Box 66)
    - Gruppe 47
      See: Subject Files
      See: Audiovisual Material
    - Literarisches Colloquium Berlin, 1990, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Literary Translations: A German-American Dialogue (New York), 1992 (Box 67)
    - Symposium 70: Günter Grass, 1970 (Box 67)
    - Other professional organizations and meetings, 1990-1998 (Box 67)
  - Teaching Materials
    - Discovery: Research and Scholarship at the University of Texas at Austin, 1976 September (Box 67)
      Mechanicals and art work for the inaugural issue
    - Other teaching materials, 1973 (Box 67)
    - Letters of recommendation (Box 68)
      Restricted until 2085. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Course materials (Box 68)
    - Course materials (Box 69)
    - Financial papers (Box 69)
- Graphic Materials, Series VI; 1; (1 box)
  Photographs include images of A. Leslie Willson, German authors, and other colleagues. A disbound album contains photographs of German authors taken by Willson during a trip to Germany in 1979; these photographs are identified on versos and in an accompanying list made by Willson. Slides showing German authors, artists, and their works were apparently used by Willson in teaching. A group of slides titled "Author/Artist Slides & Author Portraits" is accompanied by a list made by Willson. Visual art consists of drawings, prints, and posters, with some related photographs and printed reproductions. Most relate to visual art published in Dimension or by Eremiten-Presse (Düsseldorf, Germany). Some items are inscribed to Willson or are accompanied by related writings and correspondence.
  Organized into two subseries: Photographs and Slides; and Visual Art.
  - Photographs and Slides
    See also: Visual Art and Series I, Subject Files
    - Photograph album, 1979 (Box 70)
      With list of contents by A. Leslie Willson
    - Other photographs (Box 70)
      Includes: Hans Bender, Günter Grass, Uwe Johnson, Günter Kunert, Gerhard Köpf, A. Leslie Willson, and others
    - "Author/Artist Slides & Author Portraits" (Box 70)
    - "Grass Graphics" (Box 70)
      Images relating to Günter Grass
    - Other slides (Box 70)
  - Visual Art
    - Drawings and prints (Box 70)
      Includes prints by: Anthony Canham; Gertrude Degenhardt (Büchergilde Gutenberg calendar, 1986); Erich Fitzbauer (1971); Günter Bruno Fuchs; Helmut A. P. Grieshaber (woodcuts, Eremiten-Presse); Gerhard Grimm (prints and calendars, 1977); Aldona Gustas; Ludwig Harig and Cecil King, (Galway: Kinvara Press); Roger Herman (1970); Wolfgang Hildesheimerl; Günter Kunert; Christoph Meckel; Erica Pedretti; Peter Weiss (Bo Cavefors Bokförlag, 1963)
    - Posters
      Includes posters relating to: Friedrich Dürrenmatt (Diogenes Verlag); Hubert Fichte; the German-American tercentennial (Munich: Heinz Moos Verlag, 1983); Günter Grass, Uptight (premiere at the University of Austin); other events related to Günter Grass; Helmut A. P. Grieshaber (Margarethe Hannsmann, Blei im Gefieder, Eremiten-Presse); Roger Herman; Hugo Loetscher (Diogenes Verlag); Peter Pabisch
- Audiovisual Materials, Series VII; 6.8; (10 boxes)
  Organized into five subseries: Lists by A. Leslie Willson, Reel-to-Reel Tapes, Videocassettes, Cassette Tapes, and Long-Playing Records.
  Most materials are sound recordings of lectures, Gruppe 47 conferences, readings by authors, Hörspiele (radio plays), or interviews of authors by Willson. A small number of unidentified videocassettes are present. Accompanied by item-level lists made by Willson.
  - Lists by A. Leslie Willson
    - Lists of reel-to-reel tapes, cassette tapes, and long-playing records (Box 70)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Bender, Hans. "Zur Beurteilung der modern Literature," seminar lectures (University of Texas at Austin), 1968-1969; (7 tapes) (Box 71)
      Contents include: Jürgen Becker; Heissenbüttel read on Gruppe 47 tape, critics speak; Krolow: Der Baum; Paul Celan: Heimkehr; Hans Arp's new poem, Gondelfahren, Arp; Die Baloonfahrer; characteristic trends and authors of post-war German literature; new poem: Herburger; summation of contemporary trends; comment by Hugo Friedrich on modern poetry of post-war years
      - "Zur Beurteilung der modernen Literatur", 1968 November 6-22; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618500)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Zur Beurteilung der modernen Literatur", 1968 September 25-October 11; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618518)
      - "Zur Beurteilung der modernen Literatur", 1968 November 25-December 18; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618492)
      - "Zur Beurteilung der modernen Literatur", 1968 December 20-1969 January 10; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618559)
      - I. Karl Krolow (cont'd): Comments by Hugo Friedrich on modern poetry of post-war years; II. Heimkehr Paul Celan, 1968 December 11-13; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618526)
      - I. End of Paul Celan's Heimkehr, New poem: Gondel Fahren; II. End of comments on Hans Arp's Gondel Fahren, New poem: Die Ballonfahrer, 1968 December 16-18; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618534)
      - I. Die Ballonfahrer; II. Characteristic trends and authors of post-war German literature, 1968 December 20 - 1969 January 6; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618542)
    - Bender, Hans. Lectures, (32 lectures on 16 tapes) (Box 71)
      - Lectures 1 + 2, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618567)
      - Lectures 3 + 4, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618575)
      - Lectures 5 + 6, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618583)
      - Lectures 7 + 8, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618591)
      - Lectures 9 + 10, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618609)
      - Lectures 11 + 12, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618617)
      - Lectures 13 + 14, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618625)
      - Lectures 15 + 16, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618633)
      - Lectures 17 + 18, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618641)
      - Lectures 19 + 20, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618658)
      - Lectures 21 + 22, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618666)
      - Lectures 23 + 24, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618674)
      - Lectures 25 + 26, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618682)
      - Lectures 27 + 28, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618690)
      - Lectures 29 + 30, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618708)
      - Lectures 31 + 32, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618716)
    - Bender, Hans. Colloquia, 1968-1969, 1979; (5 tapes) (Box 71)
      Contents include: Programm und Prosa der jungen deutschen Schriftsteller; Literarisches Leben in Deutschland; Von der Story zum Text; Über politische Gedichte; Hans Bender reads Hans Bender
      - Tape 1, 1968 October 7, December 2; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618450)
      - Tape 2, 1968 October 21, November 4; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618468)
      - Tape 3, 1968 December 16; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618476)
      - Tape 4, 1969 January 13; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618484)
      - Bender, 1979 December 11; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618443)
    - Gruppe 47 conferences, Berlin, 1962; (8 tapes) (Box 71)
      - 1st broadcasting / tape 1, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618435)
      - 1st broadcasting / tape 2, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618427)
      - 1st broadcasting / tape 3, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618419)
      - 1st broadcasting / tape 4, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618401)
      - 2nd broadcasting / tape 1, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618393)
      - 2nd broadcasting / tape 2, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618385)
      - 2nd broadcasting / tape 3, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618377)
      - 2nd broadcasting / tape 4, 1962; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002104618369)
    - Gruppe 47 conferences, 1962-1967; (26 tapes) (Box 72)
      Contents: Berlin, 1962, second broadcast (2 tapes); Sweden, 1964 (7 tapes; 2 copies of no. 1); Berlin, 1965 (7 tapes); Princeton, 1966 (7 tapes); Pulvermühle, 1967 (2 tapes)
    - Hörspiele (radio plays), (10 tapes) (Box 72)
    - Hörspiele (radio plays), (19 tapes) (Box 73)
      - Untitled, Maschine Nr. 9, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618898)
      - Machine Nr. 9, Tape 42, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618906)
      - Tape 41, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618914)
      - Tape 36: Hauset, Jurgen Becker, Deutsche Sommerschule, 1978 Summer; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618922)
      - Tape 35: Jürgen Becker: Häuser, Sommerschule in Taos, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618930)
      - Tape 34: Mana bittet zu läuten, Gunter Eich; Hausierer Geschiechte, Güunter Bruno Fuchs, Die seltsamste Liebes geschichte der Welt, Peter Hirche, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618948)
      - Tape 24: Radio Plays, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618955)
      - Tape 29: Radio Plays, Gunter Herburger: Exhibition: or "A Battle for Rome" produced at UT/Austin by Richard Mills, tape 1, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618963)
      - Tape 30: Radio Plays; Gunter Herburger: Exhibition UT/Austin, Tape 2, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618971)
      - Tape 18: Radio Plays, "Der Mann Auf Der Strasse"; "Fliegen Im Bernstein", undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618989)
      - Tape 23: Radio Plays, "Tonband I", undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618997)
      - Tape 22: Wolf Biermann, Köln. "Das geht sein" sozialistischen Gang", sides 3 + 4, 1976 November 13; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619003)
      - Tape 21: Wolf Biermann, Köln. "Das geht sein sozialistischen Gang", sides 1 + 2, 1976 November 13; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619011)
      - Tape 17: Radio Plays, "Tonband IV", undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619029)
      - Tape 16: duplicate of 15, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619037)
      - Tape 15: Radio Plays, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619045)
      - Tape 13: Radio Plays, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619052)
      - Tape 12: Radio Plays, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619060)
      - Tape 14: Radio plays, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104619078)
    - Other subjects, 1969-1977, undated; (17 tapes) (Box 73)
      Contents include: Jürgen Becker (1977); Horst Bienek (from Werkstattgespräch mit mir selbst, Austin, 1973 February); Heinrich Böll address (1971 November 23); Günter Grass (including PBS, 1971 spring)
      - Häuser (Taos), 1978 (1977?) Summer; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618724)
      - Jürgen Becker: Häuser. Workshop tap, die deutschen sommerschule in Taos Ski-Tal, Tape 31, 1977 Summer; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618732)
      - Jürgen Becker: Häuser. Inszenierung det deutschen sommerschule von New Mexico in Taos bei Santa Fe, Tape 28, 1977 Summer; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618740)
      - Taos Sommerschule, Karlhans Frank: Der sechste Tag, Tape 43, 1982; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618757)
      - Heinrich Böll, 1971; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618765)
        A note attached to the audiotape, dated November 24, 1971, reads: Dr. Weinstocls: This is a copy of Herr Bölls talk yesterday. The original is 1/2 mil (very thin). Do you want the original or should the Language Lab buy it? Would you like another copy perhaps? Sincerely, Tony J. [?]
      - Horst Bienek from "Wekstattgesspräch mit mir selbst", Austin, 1973 February; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618773)
      - Günter Grass: Die Blechtrommel, Falter + gluhbirine, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618781)
      - Günter Grass - special report, 1973; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618799)
        A note, dated April 5, 1973, is included with the audiotape reel. It reads: Dr. Willson: Sir, thought maybe you would like to have the tape of Guenter Grass I made of a "Channel 9" program one time-about Spring of '71, I believe. He reads a couple of his poems, one unpublished, gives some "background detail"* of his life which you have already given us, and speaking both in English and German, makes a political speech. (Sorry, but I'd never especially thought he was that great-I read the 'wrong' poem first, or stopped reading too soon or something, but one of those poems in "Gleisdrieck" "turned me off", possibly upon re-reading the book, it was my own bad translation of the poem! But when I did the tape, I was trying to 'see' him as you presented him so enthusiastically in "Dimension"...so you gather he's not my 'greatest' personality as a poet - maybe he is, and I just don't see "all" of him...but I even considered "Katz und Maus" a tragedy, and they said on the cover of English translation it was a comedy! and so I stuck with having read the German version and didn't go any further). So keep the tape, please, if it is of interest to you at all and you happen not to already have it...with my "Yevtushenlo" and "Akhmatova" tapes I wouldn't part for anything. Grass I'll probably never play again, and anyway made a part tape of his poetry readings, in case I wanted it later, on my daughter's small recorder. Let's see, my recorder is a Wollensak, which I think is the same as the one you had in class - did the tape at a speed of 3 3/4, and it is rolled back on tape for playing (well, I dont really know anything about doing this sort of thing ... and only had to learn to "get it on tape", so I could 'survive' Ger. 406, as I didn't have all that much time to spend in U.T. tapelabs. PLEASE DO KEEP THE TAPE, as I have no special use for it.
        *dedicated to the memory of Walt Disney__isn't that beautiful of him?
      - Grass 1+2A, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618807)
      - Grass 1+2A, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618815)
      - Grass 1+2A, French verbs and answers, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618823)
      - Grass 2B-3A, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618831)